ANEESA AWALUDIN

Senior Front End Developer

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia • a_aneesa@yahoo.com • LinkedIn • Website

Summary

I'm a front-end developer with 15+ years of experience. I started as a release engineer at an American tech company, and have since worked with a bank, a startup, and now at a software house, mainly as a web developer.

Skills

Current Stack Javascript • TypeScript • HTML • CSS • Tailwind • Next.is

Previous Stack React Native • Shell Scripting • Ionic • Angular • Sails.js • Native Android • JAVA • Spring Boot •

Apache Maven • Hibernate • Perl • PHP • Ruby • MySQL • PostgreSQL • NoSQL

Languages English (fluent) • Malay (native) • Japanese (N3)

Experience

Shortcut Asia Sdn. Bhd.

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Senior Front End Developer

2017 - Present

A web and mobile development agency in Malaysia, specializing in creating tailored software solutions to meet clients' needs.

- Developed new features and user flows to enhance app functionality for clients.
- Enhanced and resolved issues to ensure smooth user experiences.

ServisHero Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Senior Developer 2015 - 2017

A mobile-first solution connecting consumers with local service providers in South East Asia.

- Implemented features such as the in-app chat and localization.
- Re-developed the app in Native Android.

Scope International (M) Sdn. Bhd.

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Analyst Programmer

2014 - 2015

A global technology and operations hub for the Standard Chartered Group, offering various financial services and products.

- Migrated legacy functionalities into the most recent app.
- Simplified data by consolidating multiple tables into one for easier retrieval.

RealNetworks Inc Seattle, United States

Software Release Engineer

2007 - 2012

A technology company and provider of Internet streaming media delivery software and services.

- Maintained internal tools used company-wide.
- Enforced the release process across multiple Build teams.
- Maintained the integrity of the Shared Integration environment.

Education

University of Nottingham Malaysia

MSc, INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (Distinction)

Semenyih, Malaysia

2012 - 2013

University of Washington

BSc, COMPUTER SCIENCE (3.54 / 4.00)

Seattle, United States

2003 - 2007